[
{"Counter":1,"Question":"Who wrote Mahabharata?","Responses":"Valmiki,Vishwamitra,Vedavyasa","Answer":"Valmiki","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":2,"Question":"Who was the father of Pandavas?","Responses":"Paandu, Vibheeshana,Bheeshma","Answer":"Paandu","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":3,"Question":"Who made Geethopadesam to Arjuna?","Responses":"Bheeshma,Krishna,Yudhishtira","Answer":"Krishna","Type":"Optional","Hint":"Krishna did Gita upadesam to Arjun in the kurukshetra battle field"},
{"Counter":4,"Question":"Who is the grand father of Kauravas and Pandavas?","Responses":"Bheeshma,Dasaratha,Nanda","Answer":"Bheeshma","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":5,"Question":"Who helped Vedavyasa write Mahabharata?","Responses":"Ganesha,Hanuman,Krishna","Answer":"Ganesha","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":6,"Question":"Who was the father of Ghatotkacha","Responses":"Arjuna,Bheema,Duryodhana","Answer":"Bheema","Type":"Optional","Hint":"Ghatotkagaja was the son of Bheeshma"},
{"Counter":7,"Question":"Arjuna was the son of","Responses":"Draupadi,Madri,Kunti","Answer":"Kunti","Type":"Optional","Hint":"Arjuna and Bheema were brothers"},
{"Counter":8,"Question":"What was Bheema's weapon?","Responses":"Bow,Mace,Sword","Answer":"Mace","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":9,"Question":"How many brothers were kauravas","Responses":"98 102 100","Answer":100,"Type":"Optional","Hint":"Kauravaas were 100 brothers"},
{"Counter":10,"Question":"Who was the Guru of Kauravaas and Pandavaas?","Responses":"Drona,Valmiki,Vidura","Answer":"Drona","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":11,"Question":"What was the name of Arjuna's Bow?","Responses":"Dhadeechi,Kousthubam,Gandeevam","Answer":"Gandeevam","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":12,"Question":"Who was the wife of Pandavas?","Responses":"Bhanumati,Draupadi,Kunti","Answer":"Draupadi","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":13,"Question":"Who married Krishna's sister?","Responses":"Bheema,Duryodhana,Arjuna","Answer":"Arjuna","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":14,"Question":"Pandavas changed their identities and served in which King's court?","Responses":"Viraata, Karna,Nala","Answer":"Viraata","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":15,"Question":"Kunti and Madri were wives of ?","Responses":"Santanu,Pandu,Dritarashtra","Answer":"Pandu","Type":"Optional","Hint":"Paandu had two wifes - kunti and Madri"},
{"Counter":16,"Question":"What was the famous battle of Mahabharata called?","Responses":"Kurukshetra,Mahayudh,Ranabhoomi","Answer":"Kurukshetra","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":17,"Question":"Who was the eldest of Pandavas?","Responses":"Sahadeva,Bheema,Yudhishtira","Answer":"Yudhishtira","Type":"Optional","Hint":"Dharmaraja also known as Yudhistara was the eldest son of Pandavaas"},
{"Counter":18,"Question":"Who lied on the bed of arrows until death?","Responses":"Karna,Arjuna,Bheeshma","Answer":"Bheeshma","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":19,"Question":"How many chapters did Bhagavadgeeta have?","Responses":"21 11 18","Answer":18,"Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":20,"Question":"In which Yuga did Mahabharata take place?","Responses":"Tretha Yuga,Dwaapara Yuga,Kali Yuga","Answer":"Dwapara yuga","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":21,"Question":"Abhimanyu was the son of?","Responses":"Arjuna,Bheema,Yudhishtira","Answer":"Arjuna","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":22,"Question":"Hidimba was wife of?","Responses":"Arjuna,Nakula,Bheema","Answer":"Bheema","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":23,"Question":"Who was the mother of Kauravas?","Responses":"Gaandhaari,Kunti,Radha","Answer":"Gaandhaari","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":24,"Question":"Who was the mother of Bheeshma?","Responses":"Ambika,Ganga,Satyavathi","Answer":"Ganga","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":25,"Question":"Who was the Guru or teacher of Karna?","Responses":"Drona,Vidura,Parasurama","Answer":"Parasurama","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":26,"Question":"Who befriended Karna and made him the King of Anga?","Responses":"Duryodhana,Sakuni,Bheeshma","Answer":"Duryodhana","Type":"Optional","Hint":"Dhuryodhana and Karna were best friends"},
{"Counter":27,"Question":"Who won the battle of Kurukshetra?","Responses":"Kauravas,Yadavas,Pandavas","Answer":"Pandavas","Type":"Optional","Hint":"Pandavaas with the help of Krishna won the battle of Kurukshetra"},
{"Counter":28,"Question":"Who was known as Savyasachi?","Responses":"Arjuna,Sahadeva,Bheeshma","Answer":"Arjuna","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":29,"Question":"Who tried to kill pandavas by setting fire to the lax house they resided in","Responses":"Karna,Duryodhana,Indra","Answer":"Duryodhana","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":30,"Question":"Pandavas hid their weapons on which tree during their disguise for one year","Responses":"peepal, semi, neem","Answer":"semi","Type":"Optional","Hint":"During vanavasam Pandvaas his their weapons on a tree"},
{"Counter":31,"Question":"In which language was Mahabharata written?","Responses":"Hindi,Sanskrit,Tamil","Answer":"Sanskrit","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":32,"Question":"Who was the father of Bheeshma?","Responses":"Surya,Santanu,Vichitraveerya","Answer":"Santanu","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":33,"Question":"What was the capital city of Kauravas and Pandavas called?","Responses":"Hastinapura,Viratapura,Dwaraka","Answer":"Hastinapura","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":34,"Question":"Who was the blind king of hastinapura","Responses":"Duryodhana, dhritarastra, shakuni","Answer":"dhritarastra","Type":"Optional","Hint":"King Dhritarastra was blind since birth"},
{"Counter":35,"Question":"Sahadeva was good at","Responses":"astrology, cooking, raring animals","Answer":"astrology","Type":"Optional","Hint":"Sahadeva was very good at Astrology"},
{"Counter":36,"Question":"In which game did Pandavas lose to Kauravas and went to exile for 13 years","Responses":"Dice, chess, archery","Answer":"Dice","Type":"Optional","Hint":"It was Pandavaas who lost in a game of dice and were forced to leave the kingdom"},
{"Counter":37,"Question":"Who injured Bheeshma in the battle?","Responses":"Drupada,Shikhandi,Satyabhama","Answer":"Shikhandi","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":38,"Question":"Who rode Arjuna's chariot in the battle?","Responses":"Krishna,Indra,Hanuman","Answer":"Krishna","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":39,"Question":"Bhagavadgeetha was recited by Krishna to","Responses":"Bheeshma, Arjuna, Yudhistara","Answer":"Arjuna","Type":"Optional","Hint":"Krishna did Gita Upadesam to Arjuna in the battlefield"},
{"Counter":40,"Question":"Who encouraged Duryodhana's evil ways?","Responses":"Bheeshma,Sakuni,Vidura","Answer":"Sakuni","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":41,"Question":"Shakuni was the brother of?","Responses":"Gaandhari,Duryodhana,Draupadi","Answer":"Gaandhari","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":42,"Question":"Who was the fisherman's daughter who married Santanu?","Responses":"Amba,Satyavati,Bhanumati","Answer":"Satyavati","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":43,"Question":"Who promised to be on the flag of Arjuna's chariot during war ?","Responses":"Krishna,Indra,Hanuman","Answer":"Hanuman","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":44,"Question":"Who was very good at horse riding and most handsome among Pandava brothers","Responses":"Arjuna,Nakula,Sahadeva","Answer":"Nakula","Type":"Optional","Hint":""},
{"Counter":45,"Question":"Which God gifted Akshayapatra to Yudhishtira?","Responses":"Surya,Krishna,Brahma","Answer":"Surya","Type":"Optional","Hint":""}
]